You'll Be My Backup
((カカシ : クッ… リン 逃げろ。
(リン)でも…。
Rin, get out of here!
But…!
You're going to get in my way!
足手まといだ。
土遁！
Earth Style!
土流壁！
Mud Wall!
Damn, they got away!
(バブ)チッ 逃げたか。
(バブ)うわっ！
(イナギ)土遁の中から…。
Wha—?!
From inside the Earth Style?!
リン。
すぐに治療します。
Rin!
I'll start treatment immediately!
(ミナト)どうした カカシ。
What happened, Kakashi?!
ミナト先生 オビト…。
Minato Sensei!
Obito…
(オビト)えっ カカシ リン…。
なんで俺こんなとこに…。
Kakashi? Rin?
What am I doing here?
I'll explain later.
説明はあと。 それより カカシ
これは どういうことだ？
First, Kakashi…
What happened here?
ここまで護衛の者たちと
たどり着いたのですが→
We escorted them safely to this point,
２人が裏切って…。
but the other two were traitors…
Two of them?
２人？
(イワト)頼む…。
Please, I'm not going to make it.
俺は もう助からない。
密書の中身を…。
The contents of the secret missive…
しかし
我々が中身を見ることは…。
But we can't look at its contents…
かまわない。
本物であるか 確認してくれ。
Don't worry about it.
Please, just confirm that
it's the real one.
What does this mean?
これは どういうことです？
私の上官に 私か
同じ班の誰かもう１人に→
My superior told me that
another teammate and I would
both be handed secret missives.
密書を渡すと言われていた…。
そのどちらかが本物であると。
どうして…。
And only one of them would
be the real one.
Why?!
仲間に裏切り者がいるかも
しれないという→
There was intel that there could be
a traitor among us.
情報があったからだ。
じゃあ 本物の密書は？
So who has the real missive?
If the traitor had it,
he wouldn't have attacked me.
裏切り者が持っていれば
私を襲うはずはない ならば…。
So…
彼か…。
カカシ もう１人は…。
It was him.
Kakashi, where's the other guy?
それが 途中で…。
Well, on our way here…
頼む 必ず密書を…。
Please, you must get
the secret missive!
ダメです。
There's nothing I can do.
しまった 聞かれていたか。
Damn it, did they hear us?
カカシ お前 まさか
もう１人を見捨てたのか？
Kakashi.
You didn't leave someone
to die, did you?
俺は 任務を優先させただけだ。
I only prioritized the mission.
掟に従ったまでだ。
掟…。
I followed the rules.
The rules?
掟を守らないヤツは クズだ。
Those who don't follow
the rules are scum.
だけど その結果がこれかよ。
But look at the result!
If you hadn't turned your back
on your comrade,
お前が 仲間を見捨てなきゃ
こんなことになってねえ！
this wouldn't have happened!
Stop, Obito!
やめるんだ オビト。
This was an unexpected incident.
これは 想定外の出来事だ。
カカシのせいじゃない。
Kakashi is not to blame.
Damn it!
クソッ！ 俺は行くぜ。
I'm going!
Go where?
(カカシ)どこに行く気だ？
(オビト)決まってんだろ！
Isn't it obvious?!
I'm going to save that guy!
ソイツを 助けにだよ。
But he's right in
the unexpected incident.
だが 彼は
もう敵の真っただ中だ。
He's right. It's too dangerous.
そのとおりだ 危険すぎる。
初陣で
任務失敗なんて やなこった。
I'm not about to fail
my first mission!
失敗ではない。
これは想定外のことだ。
We didn't fail.
This was an unforeseen occurrence!
カカシ お前 優等生のくせに
頭の回転が悪いな。
Kakashi, for an honor student,
you're pretty dumb.
なに！
よく考えろ。
What did you say?
Think about it.
俺たちが護衛してた４人が
全員消えたんだ。
The four guys we were supposed
to guard have all disappeared.
誰が 俺たちに
想定外のことが起きたって→
Who's gonna support our claim
that this was all unexpected?
証明してくれるんだよ？
もともと
裏切り者がいたってことを→
If the village who requested
this mission
pretends to not have known
about the traitors…
依頼してきた里に
シラを切られたら→
責任を負うのは ミナト先生だ。
Minato Sensei will be forced
to take responsibility!
俺のことは どうでもいい。
任務は終わったんだ オビト。
Never mind me.
Our mission is over, Obito.
言っときますけど→
All I want to say is…
先生が俺をぶん殴って
里に連れ戻そうが→
Sensei, you can keep dragging me
back to the village,
何度だって
置いてきぼりにされたヤツを→
but I won't give up searching
for the guy.
探しにいきますよ。
俺は 仲間を見捨てない。
I never turn my back
on a comrade!
(ミナト/リン)オビト！
– Obito!
Damn it.
ったく…。
止めてもムダのようだね。
I guess it's useless to try
and stop you.
では俺は 彼が落ちた場所。
Then I'll go back to where he fell.
その下流を カカシ。
更に下流を オビトだ。
Kakashi, you check downstream.
And Obito, check beyond that.
リンは カカシについてゆけ。
はい！
Rin, you go with Kakashi.
Right!
いいかい？ 彼を見つけたら
すぐに俺に報告するんだ。
Listen up. Report to me
the minute you find him.
(シンブ)ぐっ…。
あっ… ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
いたぞ！
He's here!
見つけたぞ。
We found him.
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
チッ…。
There are too many enemies.
《敵が多すぎる》
雷遁 千鳥！
Lighting Style! Chidori!
ぐあ～！
Are you all right?!
大丈夫ですか？
リン 彼を！
Rin! Take care of him!
わかった！ 逃げます。
Got it!
Let's get away from here.
Wait!
待ってくれ。 巻物が…。
The scroll!
引きあげる！
Withdraw!
くっ… オビト リン！ 彼を守れ。
Obito! Rin!
Guard him!
カカシ！ お前は!?
巻物を奪い返す。
What about you, Kakashi?!
I'm getting the scroll back!
無茶だ。 あの数だぞ。
That's reckless!
You saw how many there were!
文句は 言わせない。
彼を救ったのが お前の流儀なら→
I won't let you complain!
If saving him is your Ninja Way,
completing the mission is mine.
任務を遂行するのが 俺の流儀だ。
(オビト)カカシ！
(リン)オビト ミナト先生に連絡を。
Kakashi!
Obito, we have to contact
Minato Sensei!
ああ。
Yeah!
オビト…。
Obito!
(イナギ)キサマ １人で
俺たちの相手をするつもりか。
You bastard, do think you can
take us all on by yourself?
任務は やり遂げる。
I will complete my mission.
やれ。
Kill him.
(ミナト)オビト 見つけたのか？
Obito! Did you find him?
カカシが巻物を追って 敵の中に！
カカシが…。
Kakashi went after the enemy
to get the scroll back!
Kakashi did what?
間に合ってくれ。
I hope I make it in time!
(イナギ)フン！ 来い。
Come on!
ぐあっ… ソイツを逃がすな！
Don't let him…get away!
(ミナト)螺旋閃光 超輪舞吼参式！
Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
ミナト先生。
Minato Sensei.
これで やりとおせたかな？
キミの信じる流儀は。
So, were you able to uphold
the principles you believe in?
(ミナト)これで
無事に任務は 完了ですね。
This completes the mission.
ええ ありがとう。
私の命を救ってくれて。
Yes…
Thank you for saving my life.
木ノ葉の黄色い閃光。
また どこかで。
The Yellow Flash of the Leaf…
I hope we meet again someday.
では これで。 行こう みんな。
All right then, let's go everyone.
先生 本当の任務って
大変なんですね。
Sensei, missions are
really difficult, aren't they?
そうだね。 頭の中で描いたように
きれいにはいかない。
You're right.
Things don't always go
the way you envision them.
でも 密書が
無事に届けられてよかった。
But I'm glad the secret missive
was delivered safely.
ああ…。
Yes…
とにかく 任務は 達成できたな。
So we successfully
completed the mission.
おそらくな。
Probably.
おそらく？ 何 言ってんだ？
"Probably"? What do you mean?
彼は あのとき…。
Back there, he said…
((ありがとう。
私の命を救ってくれて))
Thank you for saving my life.
任務が達成できていたなら→
If the mission was successful,
自分の命より
密書のことを口にしたと思う。
he would be more concerned
about the secret missive
and not his life.
それって どういうことだよ。
What do you mean?!
彼の持っていた密書も白紙だ。
The missive he had
was also a fake.
は？
きっと俺たちは→
We were probably decoys.
陽動に使われたんだ。
Another team delivered
the real missive.
本物は 別の部隊が
運んだんだろう。
それが Ｃランクの任務に
ミナト先生を指名してきた→
That's the real reason
they requested Minato Sensei
for a C-rank mission.
本当の理由だ。
With Minato Sensei as the escort,
ミナト先生ほどの忍が護衛につけば→
俺たちが いかにも
本物を運んでいるように見える。
it would seem that we were
really guarding the real thing.
お前 いつから そのことに？
When did you figure that out?
最初の巻物がニセモノだったとき
その可能性は考えていた。
I thought it was a possibility
when we discovered
the first missive was a fake.
それじゃ お前 ニセモノかもしれない
巻物を命がけで…。
And you risked your life
to go after a missive
that could have been a fake?
それが任務だ。
That was the mission.
That's my Ninja Way.
(それが 俺の流儀だ))
(オビト)俺は お前のことを
少しは理解していると思っていた。
I thought I understood
a little about you.
But I didn't understand a thing…
だが 俺は
何もわかっちゃいなかった。
それを知ったのは
お前との最後の任務だった。
I finally understood…
on our last mission together.
((カカシは 木ノ葉の白い牙と
恐れられた 天才忍者→
Kakashi is the son of
the genius Ninja, Sakumo Hatake,
feared as the "White Fang"
of the Leaf.
はたけサクモさんの息子でね。
白い牙？
The White Fang?
それじゃ あのときの人が…。
Then that incident?
でも カカシのヤツ
ひと言もそんなこと…。
But…
Kakashi's never said
a word about him.
里の誰もが もちろん カカシも
尊敬する すばらしい人だった。
He was a great man…
Someone respected by everyone
in the village,
and naturally, by Kakashi himself.
あの事件が起きるまでは…。
That is, until that incident…
事件？
Incident?
こんなことを勝手に話しちゃ
いけないのかもしれないけど→
Perhaps, I shouldn't be telling you
something like this…
カカシと同じ班のキミには
知っておいてほしいんだ。
But since you're on
the same team as Kakashi,
I want you to know.
何があったの？
What happened?
カカシの父 サクモさんは→
Kakashi's father, Sakumo,
took his own life after being slandered.
中傷されて ご自分で
自分の命を絶たれたんだ。
５年前 ある極秘任務で→
Five years ago,
he was the leader of a top-secret mission
to infiltrate enemy territory.
隊長として 敵地に潜入した彼は→
そこで二択を迫られた。
He was forced to make a choice.
任務遂行か 仲間の命か。
To execute the mission
or save his comrades' lives…
もちろん 里の掟に従えば
任務放棄はご法度。
Of course, according to
the rules of the village,
completing the mission
was the right thing to do.
だが 彼は 仲間の命を救うため
任務を中断したんだ。
However, in order to save
the lives of his comrades,
he suspended the mission.
しかし そのことで
大きな損失を出した火の国や→
That resulted in grave losses
to the Land of Fire and the village,
里の仲間は彼を責めた。
and he was blamed for it.
あげくの果てには
助けた仲間たちでさえ→
What's more, the very comrades
he saved also criticized him.
彼を中傷したんだ。
それがもとで 心も体も悪くした
サクモさんは 自ら…。
The whole ordeal took its toll on
Sakumo, both physically and mentally.
And finally, he took his own life.
カカシは それ以来 親父さんのことを
口にしなくなり→
From then on, Kakashi never uttered
a word about his father,
掟やルールを守ることに
固執し始めた。
and he strictly began to adhere
to every rule and regulation.
(ミナト)オビト 少しでもいい。
わかってあげてね。
Obito… Try to understand,
even if it's just a little.
カカシにも
悪気があるわけじゃないんだ。
Kakashi means well.
《火遁 豪火球の術！》
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
(リン)キャ～ッ！
(タイセキ)コイツは預からせてもらう。
We're taking this one.
待て！
Wait!
(オビト)チクショウ！
オビト！
Damn it!
Obito, don't go after them!
ヤツらを追うな！
(オビト)何だと!?
What did you say?
２人で このまま任務を続行する。
The two of us will continue
this mission.
お前 今 何言ってんのか
自分で わかってんのか!?
Do you realize what you just said?!
Yeah…
ああ。
忍なら 仲間を犠牲にしてでも
任務の遂行が絶対だ。
A shinobi must sacrifice a comrade
if the mission is at stake.
それが 掟だ。
That's the rule.
お前 そんなもんのために
今まで生死をともにしてきた→
You're willing to simply abandon
a comrade
who's been through
life and death with you,
仲間を簡単に
切り捨てられるっていうのか!?
for something like that?!
お前は何も わかっちゃいない！
You don't understand anything…
掟を破ったヤツが どうなるか。
about what happens to people
who break the rules.
(オビト)俺は 白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
I believe the White Fang
was a true hero.
確かに 忍の世界で→
It's true. In the Shinobi World,
ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
someone who breaks the rules
and regulations is regarded as scum…
けどな 仲間を大切にしないヤツは→
But…
those who abandon their comrades
are worse than scum!
それ以上のクズだ！
《オビト : 見つけたぞ》
I found them…
(オビト)カカシ お前 どうして…。
Kakashi… Why are you—?!
白銀の髪に その白光のチャクラ刀。
That silver-white hair and
White Chakra Blade!
まさか お前 木ノ葉の白い牙!?
Don't tell me you're…
the "White Fang" of the Leaf?!
これは 父の形見だ。
This is a memento of my father's.
なるほどな 白い牙のガキか。
なら ビビる必要はねえな。
I see. You're the White Fang's kid.
Then there's no need
to be afraid of you.
(オビト)どこだ？
Where is he?
Obito, behind you!
オビト！ 後ろだ!!
ぐあっ！ 眼が…。
My eye!
(オビト)カカシ!!
Kakashi!
うっ…。
忍が泣くなっての。
A shinobi shouldn't cry…
まだ死んだわけじゃない。
I'm not dead yet.
気を抜くなよ。
Don't lose focus.
《オビト : 俺は いつも口先だけで…。
I'm always just talk…
みんなに助けられてばっかだ。
Other people are always saving me…
けど…》
But…
((オビト : 仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ))
Those who abandon their comrades
are worse than scum!
《あの言葉だけは
口先だけにしたくはないんだ》
I don't want them
to be empty words.
《タイセキ : 死ね！》
Die!
(タイセキ)な… なぜだ？
見えるわけはない…。
H-How?
There's no way you can see me!
オビト お前…。
Obito…You—!
(な… なんだ？ その眼は…))
W-What is that eye?
今回は 俺が メイン。
お前が バックアップだ カカシ。
This time, I'll take point and
you'll be my backup, Kakashi.
久かたぶりのツーマンセルだな。
しくじるなよ オビト。
It's been a while since
we were a two-man squad.
Don't stumble, Obito.
覚悟は いいか？
ああ。
Are you prepared for this?
Yeah…
最後の作戦が
お前とでよかったよ。
I'm glad my final op will
have been with you.
オビト… カカシ…。
Obito…Kakashi.
(マダラ)オビト お前に預けたものを
すべて返してもらう。
Obito, I'm taking back everything
I loaned you.
特に左目が
まだ入っていなくてな。
Especially that left eye…
気になるか？ マダラ。
Are you worried, Madara?
写輪眼は 左右揃って
本来の力を発揮するもの。
You told me once that
only with both together
could the Sharingan's true power
be unleashed.
そう言ったよな。 なら…。
And so…
(マダラ)違う。
もう写輪眼ではない。 輪廻眼だ。
You're wrong. Those are Rinnegan,
not just Sharingan.
違う。
You're wrong.
(マダラ)うん？
こっちのことを言ってるんだよ。
I was talking about these eyes.
((やっと揃ったね。
We're finally all together!
(カカシ)またまた遅刻だよ！ お前は。
You're late again!
(オビト)いや 途中 いろいろあって
道に迷っちゃってさ。
A lot happened on my way here
and I got lost…
(カカシ)お前の歩く道は
いつも どんだけ→
How come every path
you take is a roundabout route?
曲がりくねってるってのよ ホント。
まっすぐ来い！
Just walk a straight line!
I told you, a lot of stuff happened
along the way!
だから 道すがら いろいろ
あったって言ってんだろうが!!
忍なら決まりを守れ。
お前の その怠慢が→
A shinobi must follow the rules!
Your carelessness could end up
putting your comrades in danger!
仲間を危機に陥れる
可能性だってあんだから。
なら 俺が お前らを守ってやる。
決まりを守るかわりによ。
Then I'll just protect you guys!
Instead of obeying the rules!
(カカシ)どの口が言ってんだ。
(オビト)眼は口ほどにものを言う。
Do you know what
you're even saying?!
Eyes speak louder than words!
俺の写輪眼が開眼したら
黙ってねえぜ！
Once my Sharingan are awakened,
they won't be silent!
はぁ～。
(カカシ)お前の写輪眼なんて→
Your Sharingan won't amount
to anything!
役立つとは思えないし そもそも
開眼してないなら黙っとけ！
Besides, they're not awakened yet,
so shut up!
You shut up!
(オビト)うるせぇ！
マスクで口隠してるくせに→
Obviously, you must talk too much
口が ものを
言いすぎなんだよ お前は！
since you have to keep
your mouth covered with a mask!
テメエこそ黙っとけ！
So you shut up!
They're not falling into line
at all, are they?
(ミナト)なかなか
足並みが揃わないね。
確かに… でもね 先生。
うん？
That's for sure.
But you know, Sensei…
(ガイ)勝負だ カカシ！
I challenge you, Kakashi!
Not you again, Beast Face!
またテメエか 猛獣顔！
来んじゃねえ！
Leave us alone!
(まったく
俺の同期どもは…))
How did I end up with
classmates like these?
《マダラ : ナルトを復活させるためには→
In order to resurrect Naruto,
輪廻眼と九尾
これらを持つオビトを→
they need the Rinnegan
and the Nine Tails.
Obito has them both,
時空間へ
飛ばしさえしなければいい。
so as long as I don't allow him
to teleport away to his time-space…
神威の移動時間より→
And I've already discovered
俺の攻撃のほうが速いのは
さっきわかった。
that my attacks are faster than
their Kamui's transfer speed.
おそらく コイツらは どちらか一方が
俺に陽動をしかけてくる間に→
There's no doubt one of them
will try to distract me
もう一方が 神威をする。
while the other performs the Kamui.
オビト自ら飛ぶか それとも
カカシに飛ばせるかの二択》
Obito will teleport himself or
have Kakashi teleport him.
((今回は 俺が メイン。
お前が バックアップだ カカシ))
This time, I'll take point and
you'll be my backup, Kakashi.
《マダラ : どちらにしろ
二択ともオビトが言ったように→
Whatever they decide,
I'll be able to stop Obito again.
とらえることができる。
手っ取り早く輪墓でいくか…。
I should keep it fast and
simple with Limbo…
いや オビトに輪廻眼がある以上
それはやるべきではない。
No… I shouldn't use that as long as
Obito still has the Rinnegan.
なら２人同時に
攻撃しさえすればいい》
Then I'll attack them
both simultaneously!
((リン : でもね 先生。
そこは私に任せて。
But you know, Sensei…
Let me handle this.
私が ２人をちゃんと…。
I'll make the two of them—!
Let's go…you guys!
(行くよ！ ２人とも！ フフッ！))
(２人)神威！
Kamui!
お互い まったく同時に神威を。
They both released their Kamui
at the same time!
術のスピードを倍にして飛ぶとはな…。
And doubled the speed of the jutsu!
(サクラ)オビト。
大丈夫だ。
Obito!
Don't worry.
俺が ナルトを助けてやる。
I'm here to help Naruto…
信用できるの？
Can I trust you?
俺は 昔から まっすぐ素直には
歩けなくってね。
Ever since I was a kid,
I've never been able to walk
a straight path.
だが やっと… たどり着いた。
But I've finally gotten to
where I needed to go.
今回ばかりは
いいときに来てくれたよ。
You actually had
perfect timing for once.
《カカシを助けてくれて
ありがとう ガイ》
Thanks for saving Kakashi…
Guy!
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
(ガイ)大丈夫か？ カカシ。
どこかで見たな。
んっ!? 誰だ？ あれ。
＜敗戦ということを知らない
日本が初めて味わった敗戦に→
１億 総国民が
虚脱状態に入りました。
その中に
爽やかに聴こえてきた歌声…＞